In this section, we'll learn a way to tell overfitting,
在这部分 我们将学习如何判断是否过拟合
欠拟合以及模型是否效果很好
under-fitting and a good model.
这是三组数据
So, here we have our data three times.
Our data seems to be well split by a quadratic equation of degree two.
我们的数据似乎按照二次方程式很好地分布
我们将尝试拟合三个模型
So, we're going to try and fit three models.
The first one, a linear or degree one model,
第一个是线性（一次）模型
效果不是太好 因为欠拟合 所以是个偏差很高的模型
which doesn't do a very good job since it under fits so it's a high bias model.
The second one, a quadratic model of degree two, which is just right.
第二个是二次方程式模型 效果不错
第三个是六次多项式
And the third one, a higher degree polynomial of degree
过拟合了 因此是高方差的模型
six which over fits so it's a high variance model.
现在我们将画出一些曲线 以便区分这些模型
Now, we'll draw some curves that will be able to tell these models apart.
先从高偏差线性模型开始
Let's start here with a high bias linear model.
我们先使用几个点训练该模型
We're going to start training the model with
very few points and increase the number of points gradually.
然后逐步增加点的数量
如果用四个点训练该模型
If we train this model with say four points,
那么可以很好地拟合训练集
we can do a pretty good job fitting the training set.
因此训练误差很小 我们将误差绘制在右侧图表中
So we have a tiny training error which we'll plot in the graph in the right,
but once we evaluate in the cross-validation data,
但是当我们评估交叉验证数据时
因为只使用四个点训练模型
well, since we have trained them all on only four points,
模型效果不会太好 因此交叉验证的误差肯定很高
it cannot be a very good model so it probably has a pretty high cross validation error.
我们不会显示交叉验证集
We won't show the cross validation set,
but you can pretty much imagine any other random subset of this data.
但是你可以想象出该数据的其他随机子集
我们将交叉验证误差绘制在这里
We plot the cross violation error over here,
and now we increase to eight points and we train the linear model again.
现在增加到 8 个点 再次训练线性模型
训练误差可能会增大一点点 因为拟合八个点比四个点要困难
The training error may increase a bit since it's harder to fit eight points than four,
but since we have a slightly better model and we've used more data to train it,
但是因为模型效果稍微好些 我们使用了更多的数据来训练它
或许交叉验证误差降低了一点点
then maybe the cross validation error has decreased a bit
but not much since it's a linear model trying to fit quadratic data.
但是幅度并不大 因为这是一个尝试拟合二次数据的线性模型
Here are the training and cross validation errors in the graph.
这是训练误差和交叉验证误差
Now, we increase to 12 points and we train the model again.
现在增多到 12 个点 重新训练模型
同样 训练误差可能会增大一点点 因为有更多的训练数据需要拟合
Once more, the training error may increase a bit since there's more training data to fit,
但是交叉验证误差也会再降低一点点
but the cross validation error will also decrease a
因为有一个用更多数据进行训练的更好模型了
bit since we have a better model to train with more data,
but it still won't decrease by much.
但是依然不会降低太多
似乎随着点的数量越来越增多
It seems that as we increase the number of points more and more,
the training error will keep increasing and the testing error will
训练误差将不断增大 测试误差
keep decreasing so if we draw these two curves,
将不断下降 如果画出这两条曲线
they'll get closer and closer to each other,
它们将越来越接近
and maybe converge at some point.
或许在某个点还会汇合
汇合的点应该很高
The point they converge should be high anyway since we don't
因为这两个模型是欠拟合的 它们的误差不会很小
expect these models to have small error as they are under-fitting.
现在对二次方程式模型执行相同的操作
Now, let's do the exact same thing with
the quadratic model so let's remember that this is the good model.
记住这个模型效果很好
Training with four points, just as before,
和之前一样 用四个点进行训练
we can do pretty well in the training set so we have a small training error,
训练集的效果很好 因此训练误差很小
but since we trained the model in very few points,
但是只用了非常少的点训练模型
因此交叉验证集的结果可能不太理想
we probably didn't do very well in the cross validation
set so our cross validation error is large.
因此交叉验证误差很大
Now, if we increased to eight points, again,
如果将点增多到 8 个
our training error increases since we have more points to fit,
训练误差增大了 因为有更多的点要拟合
但是因为模型用更多的点进行训练 了解的信息更多
but since our model knows more as it's trained on more points,
then the cross validation error has decreased and if we go to 12 points,
所以验证误差下降了 如果使用 12 个点进行训练
the same thing happens again.
出现同样的情况
Training error increases, cross validation error decreases.
训练误差增大了 交叉验证误差下降了
和之前一样 这两条曲线越来越接近
So, as before, these curves get closer and closer to each other except,
now they convert to a lower point since the model is
但是交点更低
good and we expect expect it to have small error.
因为模型效果很好 因此误差很小
Finally, let's do the same thing with the degree six model.
最后对六次模型执行相同的流程
注意 这个模型会过拟合
Let's remember that this is the model that over fits.
Let's train with four points.
用四个点进行训练
同样 我们可以很轻松地拟合四个点 因此训练误差很小
Again, we can fit four points very easily so we have a small training error.
因为该模型了解的信息不多
And again, as we don't have very much information for a point six model,
因此交叉验证集的效果不会很好
probably didn't do very well in the cross validation set,
so we have a large cross validation error.
因此交叉验证误差很大
现在如果将训练集增大到 8 个点
Now, if we increase the training set to eight points,
训练误差稍微大了些
we have a slightly large training error and
测试误差稍微小了些 和之前一样
a slightly smaller testing error just like before.
如果将训练集增大到 8 个点
Now, if we increase the training set to eight points,
then we have a slightly larger training error and
那么训练误差稍微大些
交叉验证误差稍微小些
a slightly smaller cross validation error and
this happens again for 12 points as we've seen before,
12 个训练点也是一样
但是现在出现了有趣的现象
but now, something interesting happens.
训练误差始终不会变得太大
The training error will never grow too large
since models that overfit tend to do very well in
因为过拟合的模型在训练集中效果会很好
因为它们可以很好地拟合
the training set as they can fit it very well
and the cross validation error will never get too low,
交叉验证误差始终不会太低
因为我们看过过拟合的模型在交叉验证集中效果不太好
since as we've seen models that overfit do not do very well in the cross validation set.
当我们增多训练点时
As we increase the number of points,
these two curves will get closer,
这两条曲线将更接近
but will not converge to the same point.
但是不会汇集成一点
There will always be a distance between them.
它们之间始终存在一定的距离
总结下 我们有三个模型
In summary, here we have three models: the high bias,
高偏差模型 效果好的模型和高方差模型
the good one and the high variance.
在高偏差（欠拟合）模型中
In the high bias or underfitting model,
the curves get close to each other and converge to a high point.
两条曲线相互接近并交于一点
在效果好的模型中
In the good model, the curves again,
曲线同样相互接近并交于一个很低的点
go close to each other and converge to a low point,
在高方差（过拟合）模型中
and in the high variance or overfitting model,
the curves do not get close to each other.
曲线没有相互接近
The training one stays low and the cross validation one stays high.
训练集保持很低 交叉验证集保持很高
So this is a way to tell between under-fitting,
这样就可以判断是否欠拟合
过拟合或者正常
overfitting, and just right.
We just look at the learning curves and see what shape they form.
我们直接查看训练曲线并看看它们的形状